(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-20T21:18:11.787925",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
スキスキスー フワフワフー
Love love, fluffy...
こんな キモチ メロメロディ
This feeling, melo melody.
夢 だけど 夢 じゃ ない
It's a dream, but not a dream.
お願い ね マイメロディ
Please, my melody.
オトナ じゃ ない
I'm not an adult,
オトメ です
I'm a maiden.
恋する の が 仕事 です
Falling in love is my job.
君 の 名前 つぶやく と
When I whisper your name,
ドキドキ する の
My heart races.
聞き分け ない この 胸 が
This disobedient heart of mine...
上手にできなくてごめんね
I'm not doing great, but sorry!
だけど聞いて
Listen carefully, okay?
届けマイメロディ
My Melody!
マイメロディ
星空を越えて 君の夢 守るリボン
Beyond the starry sky, protect your dreams, My Ribbon!
マイメロディ
My Melody!
ハート見つけたら
Once I found you're the one,
ぐるぐる巻きにしちゃうからね
I'll wrap you up in a tangle!
覚悟しといて
Be prepared,
嘘じゃない
that's no lie!
大人じゃない 乙女です
I'm not acting mature, I'm just being a maiden,
泣いたってしちゃいます
and I might even cry!
女の子って魔法で 作られたの
Created with a girl's magic!
好き好きす ふわわふ こんな気持ち メロメロディ
Thumping, fluttering, such feelings, Melo-Melody!
夢だけど 夢じゃない
It's a dream, but it's not a dream!
お願いね マイメロディ
Please, My Melody!
嫌いじゃない 手間よ好き
I don't hate you, I like you too much!
素直になんてなれません
I can never be straightforward.
君の笑顔見るだけで ふにゃふにゃするの
Just seeing your smile makes me go all weak in the knees.
それなのに それなのに
Even though you're like that...
妬まれ愚痴うちまくり ひとりになって落ち込んで
Spitting out grudges when I'm feeling down and alone,
バクダンパンチ
that's a bang-bang punch!
マイメロディ
My Melody!
本当の気持ち 風になって結ぶリボン マイメロディ
My true feelings turn into the wind and tie a ribbon, My Melody!
歌え乙女心 ぐるぐる恋 捕まえちゃうえ
Singing a maiden's heart song, I'll catch you in a tangle!
逃がさないから
I won't let you escape,
ここへ来て
so come over here!
嫌いじゃない 辛いです
I don't hate you, it's just so tough!
真っ赤にだってなっちゃいます
Even my face goes completely red!
女の子って不思議で作られたの
A girl's magic is so mysterious!
マイメロディ
My Melody!
星空を越えて 君の夢 守るリボン
Beyond the starry sky, protect your dreams, My Ribbon!
マイメロディ
My Melody!
ハート見つけたら ぐるぐる巻きにしちゃうからね
Once I found you're the one, I'll wrap you up in a tangle!
覚悟しといて
Be prepared,
嘘じゃない
that's no lie!
大人じゃない 乙女です
I'm not acting mature, I'm just being a maiden,
泣いたってしちゃいます
and I might even cry!
女の子って魔法で 作られたの
Created with a girl's magic!
好き好きす ふわわふ こんな気持ち メロメロディ
Thumping, fluttering, such feelings, Melo-Melody!
夢だけど 夢じゃない
It's a dream, but it's not a dream!
お願いね マイメロディ
Please, My Melody!
マイメロディ
My Melody!
今日から君の好きなとこ 一日一個伝えよう
Today, I'll tell you one thing I like about you,
365回ドキドキさせちゃうぜ バッキューン！
making your heart skip a beat 365 times, bang!
「こっちにおいでよ」もう
"Come over here," you said.
もしかして まだ 片思い？
Could it be you're still unrequited?
たまに 甘えてくるくせに
Even though you sometimes come crying to me to be spoiled!
もしかして 転がされてる？ ひとめぼれして
Could it be I'm the one being swept off my feet, staring at you wide-eyed?
毎日通ってた 君と目が合う度に 恋が爆発
Every time our eyes meet, my love explodes!
今日から君の好きなとこ 一日一個伝えよう
Today, I'll tell you one thing I like about you,
365回ドキドキさせちゃうぜ バッキューン！
making your heart skip a beat 365 times, bang!
ほかのところを見たり 携帯ばかり見たり
Looking around everywhere, or just staring at your phone?
君だけ見てるよ 偉いのご褒美は？ チュウ
I'm only looking at you. What's my reward? Chu!
「たまにはお出かけどう？」
"How about we go out somewhere for a change?"
「いつも部屋デートばっかりじゃん？」
"We always just date in our rooms, don't we?"
もいいけど
Even if it's fine,
僕だってオシャレしたいし
I want to dress up nicely too.
気分屋な君
Moody you,
世話が焼けるな
You're such a handful.
僕がいないと 何もできないくせに
Even though you can't do anything,
毎日君の機嫌取って 一日いっぱいハグして
Keeping you happy every day,
何百回何千回 愛を伝えちゃうぜ
I love you hundreds, thousands of times!
バッキューン！
Bang!
独りにしちゃったり ゲームばっしたり 君だけ見てるよ
Leaving you alone or playing games,
偉いのご褒美は？ ちゅー！
What's my reward for being good? A kiss!
帰るの遅くなりそうだけど
I might be late getting home today,
急いで帰るからね 寄り道せずに愛の巣「ただいまー！」
So I'll rush back to our nest of love.
「おかえり」もナシ？ 「よしよし」もナシ？
No "welcome back"? No "there, there"?
それでもいいよ だから 一緒にいてね
Even so, that's fine, so stay with me.
ねぇねぇどこ隠れてるの もしかして出てていいじゃんっ！
Hey, where are you hiding?
急に飛びついてきた 君は小悪魔だね
You suddenly leaped onto me, little devil.
今日から君の好きなとこ 一日一個伝えよ
Starting today, I'll tell you my love daily.
365回 ドキドキさせちゃうぜ
365 times, I'll make your heart race!
バッキューン！
Bang!
他のとこ見たり 携帯ばっか見たり 君だけ見てるよ
Looking elsewhere or staring at your phone—
偉いのご褒美は？ ちゅー！
What's my reward for being good? A kiss!
はーい！
Heeey!
というわけで、今日は遅めの誕生日ライブということで
So, today is a belated birthday live,
みんな見に来てくれてありがとー！イエーイ！
thank you everyone for coming! Yay!
ダンスもね、歌もたくさん頑張ったので、細かいところまでたくさん注目して見てほしいなって思います。
I worked really hard on dancing and singing,
ま、そんなこんなでね、今2曲ちょうど終わったところなんですけど、「乙女ロディー」と「小悪魔だってかまわない！」でした！
We just finished two songs,
どうでしたか、みなさん？
How was it, everyone?
どうでしたか？可愛かった？
Was it cute?
そう、「乙女ロディー」も「小悪魔だってかまわない！」って、あの演出がね、ある感じにしたんですけど
For both songs, we added special staging,
ちょためちゃめちゃ可愛くね、作ってもらったからね、それもね、ちゃんとアーカイブとかでも細かいところまでちゃんと見てほしいですね。ありがとうございます！
so check out the fine details in the archive.
というわけで、イラストの方はどうでしたか？みんな気づきましたか？絵が変わってたの。
Did everyone notice the illustrations changed?
あ、今はね、これサムネのイラストなんだけど、めちゃめちゃ可愛いでしょう？こうやって、こうやってする。めちゃめちゃ可愛いでしょ？
This is the thumbnail illustration, right?
そう、で、次が「乙女ロディー」のイラストなんですけど、めちゃめちゃ可愛いもうこれ、なもり先生がね、描いて貰いました。めちゃめちゃ可愛い！本当に可愛い！
Namori-sensei drew this for me. So cute!
で、次、うさぎです。
And next, a rabbit.
で、次が「小悪魔だってかまわない！」
Next is "Koakuma Datte Kamawanai!"—cute!
かわいい！これ、さくらひより先生に描いて貰いました。可愛いね！
Sakura Hiyori-sensei drew this for me!
こんな、こんな小悪魔いたらね、いたずらされてもね、みんな許しちゃうよね？
You'd forgive her even if she pranked you.
はい！というわけで、こんな感じで他のね、あの全部のコラボ曲とかも、まだあるソロ曲とかも、あのイラストがね、あるから、ぜひね後ろの画面にもねみんな注目して見てください！
For all other collab and solo songs too,
というわけで、今日はこの後はゲスト、ゲスト続きととなっております。
After this, we have a guest lineup.
あんまり3Dで並んだことないゲストもね、ここ、ここにいるんだけどね、そう、二人で並んだことはないよねみたいな人を呼んでね、なんか
We invited guests who haven't 3D-collabed,
あれ、ちょっとよく、よく仲良く、あれ、結婚、結婚相手もちょっと来てるんですけど、今日は。
Even my "spouse" is actually coming today.
はい！そんな感じで、どうぞ、この後もコラボ続きたくさん見てってね！ずっと見てね！
Please enjoy all the upcoming collabs!
ばいばーい！
Bye-bye!
ネットからクマが脱走だって？
A bear escaped from the internet?
シオンも脱走してみたーい！っていうかもうこんな時間か。
I wanna try escaping too! Wait, is it already this time?
早く帰って配信の準備しないと。
I gotta head home fast and prep for stream.
うわっ！
Woah!
うわあ！
Aah!
クマが歩いて事務所に入ってきた！
A bear just walked into the office!
うわっ、やばい！
Woah, crap!
バレたら食われる！
If it sees me, I'll get eaten!
誰かに電話して助けに来てもらわないと。
I gotta call someone to come save me.
はい、何？
Hello? What?
あん、もしもしあくあ？
Um, hello, Aqua?
今事務所でクマに襲われかけてるんだけど助けに来て！
I'm almost being attacked by a bear at the office, come save me!
えー、クマすご。
Ew, a bear? Amazing.
シオン食われるから早く助けに来て！
I'm gonna get eaten, so hurry up and save me!
うん、あとでね。おっぷら。
Yeah, later. Oppura.
後ろにいたんだけど、すぐ切られた。
She was right behind me, but she hung up immediately.
お前、エーピーやってんだろ。
You're playing Apex, aren't you?
ごめん、ちょっと今忙しいからまた後で！
Sorry, I'm kind of busy right now, so catch you later!
切りやがったし。
She totally hung up on me.
だめだ、早く次の人に電話しよう。
No good, I gotta call the next person fast.
そうだ、船長！船長なら助けてくれる。
That's right, Marine! Marine will save me.
年上だし。
She's older, too.
はい、宝鐘です。
Hello, Houshou here.
船長助けて！今事務所でクマに襲われてるの！シオン食われちゃうよ！
Captain, help! I'm being attacked by a bear at the office! I'm gonna get eaten!
え、クマ？
Huh, a bear?
どんなクマ？
What kind of bear?
もうやだ！速い！目がチバしてて爪とか牙とかが1メートルくらいあって2足歩行してる。
No way! Hurry! Its eyes are bloodshot and its claws and fangs are like a meter long and it's walking bipedally.
早く助けに来て船長！
Hurry and come save me, Captain!
ああ、はいはいはい、あ、そうゆう。
Ah, yeah yeah yeah, oh, that kind.
まあ、はい。ええっと、船長はあんまりリアル系のガチクマはアウトオブガンチュウで
Well, yeah. Um, Captain isn't really into realistic hardcore bears...
ぬいぐるみみたいに可愛いモフモフのクマちゃんがタイプなんですよね。
I'm more into cute, fluffy bear plushies, you know?
なのでまあ、正直ちょっと
So honestly, well...
興味ないっす！
Not interested!
じゃ、そういうことで。
Well, anyway.
通話終了
[Call Ended]
いや、好みとか聞いてないんですけど！
Hey, I didn't ask about your type!
通話切れたし、誰も助けに来ないんだけど！
The call dropped, and nobody's coming to save me!
シオンとの絆はどこにあるんだよ！
Where is our bond with Shion?!
沙花叉？沙花叉か。
Sakamata? Sakamata, huh.
うーん、沙花叉だし行けるか？
Hmm, it's Sakamata, can she do it?
あ、シオン先輩、今日配信で
Ah, Shion-senpai, today on stream--
沙花叉助けて！事務所でクマに襲われてるの！
Sakamata, help! I'm being attacked by a bear at the office!
え？クマあしゅりば？
Huh? Bear what?
知るか、早く助けに来て！
Who cares, hurry and save me!
わかりました、待っててください。今すぐ迎えに行きます！
Understood, please wait. I'll come get you right now!
助けに来ました、シオン先輩！
I've come to save you, Shion-senpai!
お前がシオン先輩をいじめる悪いクマか？
Are you the bad bear bullying Shion-senpai?
やつけろ沙花叉、ぶちかましてやれ！
Get him, Sakamata, smash him to bits!
シャチになめさせんな！
Don't mess with an Orca!
うわあ！
Aah!
俺のシオンから離れろ！
Get away from my Shion!
やっぱだめか。
Guess it's no good.
あ、シオン先輩助けて！
Ah, Shion-senpai, help!
後輩が体を張っているこの状況で先輩であるシオンが引き下がるわけにはいかない。
In a situation where a junior is putting her body on the line, Shion as her senior cannot back down.
世間体的に
Public-image-wise...
こら、沙花叉を離せ！
Hey, let go of Sakamata!
あ
Ah
出口
[Exit]
ごめん、やっぱ帰るわ。
Sorry, I'm going home after all.
シオン先輩！
Shion-senpai!
ねぇねぇ もしものもしもだよ
Hey hey, what if, just what if
私が帰り道 グリズリーに襲われたら
I was attacked by a grizzly bear on my way home?
あなたならば どうする？
What would you do?
グリズリーに襲われたら♡
If I were attacked by a grizzly bear ♡
もしものね 帰り道
What if, you know, on my way home
グリズリーと出会って
I encountered a grizzly bear
暗闇で目が合えば今日をフデ動けないわ
And our eyes met in the darkness, I couldn't move at all today
震えるカッチビルで
With trembling lips
探せってそっと待ちたら
If I quietly whispered to search for me
あなたはすぐに来てくれますか？
Would you come right away for me?
ねぇ 嘘ついて あたしは泣かないで
Hey, lie to me, don't cry
信じてなの
Just believe in me
ごめんね お台場だって駆けつけてね
Sorry, rush all the way to Odaiba for me
一秒を争うのよ
We're fighting over every single second
わいざつに着替える前に骨まで食べられちゃうわ
Before I can change into something indecent, I'll be eaten down to the bones
ヘルプミー 裸足だって駆けつけてね
Help me, rush over even barefoot
私を男前に
Make me look manly
心配してたまらなくて走り出してほしいの
I want you to be so worried you can't help but start running
どんな人が嬉しいの？
What kind of person makes you happy?
もしものね 曲がり角
What if, you know, at a street corner
グリズリーにぶつかり
I bumped into a grizzly bear
物の影で向き合えば怖くてさけびないわ
And faced it in the shadows, I was too scared to scream
オーピエル 左手で 手つけてメールしたら
With my left hand, with OPieru, if I text you
あなたはすぐに見てくれますか？
Will you look at it right away?
ねぇ ほら聞いて カットづけないで
Hey, listen here, don't cut me off
本当の 信じて
Believe the truth
仕事だって駆けつけてね 何もかもを投げ出して
Rush over even if you're working, throwing everything aside
万業が終わるまでに捕まるのみたい
Before the workday ends, it seems like I'll be caught
ねぇねぇもしものもしもだょ？
Hey hey, what if—what if this happened?
私が帰り道グリズリーに襲われたら
If I were attacked by a grizzly bear on my way home,
貴方ならどうする？
What would you do?
もしも(もしも)貴方ならどうする？
(If—what would you do?)
もしもね帰り道グリズリーと出会って
What if on my way home, I met a grizzly bear,
暗闇で目が合えば恐怖で動けないわ
If our eyes met in the dark, I wouldn't be able to move from fear,
震える唇で助けてと電話したら
With trembling lips, if I called for help,
貴方はすぐ来てくれますか？
Would you come running right away?
ねぇ嘘付いてて阿呆じゃないで
Hey, don't brush it off as a lie,
真実なの お願い (yeah !)
It's the truth, please!
パジャマだって駆けつけてね 1秒を争うのよ
Even in your pajamas, come running, fighting over every second,
Yシャツに着替える間に骨まで食べられちゃうわ (yes help me)
While you change into your shirt, I'll be eaten to the bone (yes help me)
裸足だって駆けつけてね 私を疑う前に
Even barefoot, come running, before doubting me,
心配でたまらなくて走り出してほしいのです
I'm so worried, I want you to start running,
そんな人が嬉しいの (yeah !)
That kind of person makes me happy!
ねぇ 細付いて 足音も無いで
Hey, without even footsteps...
真実なのをねぇば
The truth is...
まだだって駆けつけてね
Even still, come running,
1秒を争うのよ
fighting over every second!
ワイシャツに着替える間に 骨まで食べられちゃうよ
While you change into your shirt, I'll be eaten down to the bone,
裸足だって駆けつけてね 私を疑う前に
Even barefoot, come running, before doubting me,
心配でたまらなくて 走り出してほしいのです
I'm so worried, I want you to start running,
そんな人が嬉しいの
That kind of person makes me happy!
心配でたまらなくて 走り出してほしいのです
I'm so worried, I want you to start running,
そんな人が嬉しいの
That kind of person makes me happy!
あなたしかいないの
There is only you!
シオン先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Shion-senpai, happy birthday!
お楽しみおめでとう！ありがとう！
Happy birthday! Thank you!
今日主演じゃないですか。
You're the star today, aren't you?
そうですよ。でも誕生日実はずっと前なんだけど。
That's right. But my birthday is actually a bit earlier.
あ、そっか。
Ah, right.
いやでも、
Well, but...
そうだよね、今日も誕生日ということで、いいよね？
That's right, since it's my birthday today too, that's fine, right?
そうだよね、そうだよね。なんていうか、微妙な雰囲気...ひどいよ！
That's right, that's right. What a vague atmosphere... How awful!
でもこの、見てくださいよ。
But look at this, please.
ああ、坂又たち仲良ピじゃないですか。仲良ピ！
Ah, Sakamata and you are close buddies, aren't you? Close buddies!
え、仲良ピやめっかな？
Eh, should I stop being close buddies?
仲良ピ、ねぇ？さっきだって言ってくれてたじゃないですか。
Close buddies, right? You just said so earlier, didn't you?
え？じゃあもう一回聞きたいな。え、なんで消え...あれ？
Eh? Then I want to hear it again. Eh, why did it disap—huh?
あれ、あれ、あれ聞きたいな！あーいうやつ、あれ欲しいな！
Huh, huh, I want to hear that! I want that kind of thing!
お、お嫁さんみたいだよね。
You look like a bride.
皆さん、坂又が今日からお嫁さんです！いぇーい！
Everyone, Sakamata is a bride starting today! Yay!
足を絡みな、ごめん。しお先輩の意向だから仕方なく、しょうがなくなんですけど。
Wrap your legs around... sorry. It's Shion-senpai's wish, so I have no choice, but...
でも、ごめん。
But, sorry.
しゅん、実は心に決めてる人がいるんだ。
Honestly, there's someone I've set my heart on.
え、え、誰ですか？
Eh, eh, who is it?
おかゆって言うんだけどさ。
Someone named Okayu, you see.
ああ、おかゆ先輩か！
Ah, Okayu-senpai!
うん。私先輩誰にでも言いますよ。
Yeah. I say that to anyone, Senpai.
え？誰にでも言ってるの？
Eh? You say that to anyone?
しゅんだけに言ってるよ。
I only say it to Shun.
え、違いますよ、違いますよ。
Eh, no way, no way.
違いますよ、違う！
No way, no!
坂又とはじゃあしゅんだけなの？
So with Sakamata, it's only Shun?
坂本とシオン先輩だけにしよう。
Let's make it only Sakamoto and Shion-senpai.
じゃあ、坂又でいっか！
Well then, Sakamata is fine!
適当じゃん！やだやだやだ！もっと違う、もっとちゃんと言って！
That's so casual! No way, no way! Say it properly!
え、でもじゃあ、なんで呼んでくれたんですか、坂又じゃないのに。
Eh, then why did you call me, even though it's not Sakamata?
え、坂又とさ、コラボはしたことあるけどさ、3Dで並んだことってないじゃん。
Eh, Sakamata and I have collaborated before, but we've never stood side-by-side in 3D.
確かに。
That's true.
だから、並びたいなと思って。で、坂又の声かわいいから。
So, I thought I wanted to stand next to you. And Sakamata's voice is cute.
声も、顔も、不気味なとこも、かわいいから。
Her voice, her face, even her eerie parts are cute.
あれ、なんか聞いたことあるな、それ。どっかのフレズに...
Huh, I've heard that somewhere before. Some kind of phrase...
かわいい曲歌いたいなと思って、今日このね、グリズリーに襲われたらって曲にしました。
I wanted to sing a cute song, so I chose this song called "If Attacked by a Grizzly".
え、でも、それってあほ、心に決めてるんでしょ？
Eh, but, you've set your heart on someone, right?
じゃあもう分かってないだけですぅ。
Then you just don't understand!
まあでも坂又でもいっか！
Well, but Sakamata is fine too!
なんでだよ！でもいいやじゃないでしょ！
Why is that?! "That's fine too" isn't right!
え、じゃあもし本当にグリズリーに襲われたらどうします、シオン先輩？
Eh, what would you do if you were really attacked by a grizzly, Shion-senpai?
えー、シオンがさ、電話したら助けに来てくれるの？
Eh—if I called you on the phone, would you come save me?
いやもう100%駆けつけますよ。
Yeah, I'll come running 100%.
あの、いつだって、どうぞどうぞどうぞ。
Whenever it is, please, please, please.
あの、そういう時じゃなくても全然出会まってるんで、はい。いつでも待ってますから。
Even when it's not a time like that, I'm totally waiting around, yes. I'm always waiting.
あの、送ってもらってもいいですか？てか、書いてもらっても...
Um, can you send it to me? Or rather, can you write it...
え、じゃあグリズリーの役やりましょうか？あ、じゃあちょっとグリズリーになるんで。
Eh, then should I play the grizzly? Ah, then since I'm going to become a grizzly...
シオン先輩のことを、ちょっとグリズリーとして襲わせていただきます！えい！
I'll attack Shion-senpai as a grizzly! Take this!
はあ、最近本当ついてないな。
Haah, things really haven't been going my way lately.
うわ、キャミング勝手に言われた！
Whoa, my camping trip was cancelled without my permission!
これじゃあシオンが終わったみたいじゃん！
This makes it look like Shion's career is over!
どうしよう、また叱られる……！
今叱られてきたばっかなのに！
What should I do? I'm gonna get scolded again...
Even though I was just scolded!
やあ、お困りかな？ お嬢さん
Hey, are you in trouble, miss?
ど、お、おかゆ？
W-W-Okayu?
いつからそこに？ なんでいんの？
Since when have you been there? Why are you here?
僕はちょっと探し物…… ギハンギハン
I'm just looking for something... heh-heh.
それより、一体どうしたんだい？
More importantly, what happened?
花瓶が勝手に落ちて割れちゃったの！
シオンのせいじゃないのに！
A vase fell and broke on its own!
Even though it's not Shion's fault!
それは災難だったね
That sounds like a disaster.
よーしよし、シオンは悪くないよ
There, there, Shion did nothing wrong.
やっぱりおかゆだけはシオンの味方になってくれる
As I thought, only Okayu takes Shion's side.
実は今ちょうど、割れた花瓶を元に戻すことだけが
存在意義の接着剤ってのを思ってるんだけど
Actually, I happen to have an adhesive
whose sole purpose is to fix broken vases.
のぞみならこれで直してあげるよ
If you want, I can fix it with this.
マジで？直して直して！
Seriously? Fix it, fix it!
はい、元通りになったよ
There, it's back to normal.
すごーい！傷ひとつないんだけど！
Amazing! There's not a single scratch!
僕にかかれば失敗なんて
全部なかったことにできちゃうよ
If it's up to me, I can make all mistakes
as if they never happened.
失敗を……なかったことに？
Make mistakes... as if they never happened?
じ、実はそこの壁に落書きしたのもシオンなんだけど、
油性で描いたから消えなくなっちゃって……
W-Well, actually, the graffiti on that wall is also Shion's,
but I drew it in oil marker so it won't erase...
うわあ、それはひどいね
Woah, that's terrible.
お願いおかゆ！この落書きもなかったことにして！
Please, Okayu! Make this graffiti never have happened too!
もちろん！今なら特別価格で
このサービスを提供できちゃうよ
Of course! Right now, I can offer
this service at a special price.
えっ……金たらんのですか？なんと今なら1万おかゆぽっきりだよ！
でもこれはタイムセール価格だからあと1分で通常価格の10万おかゆに……
Eh... do you lack money? Right now it's just 10,000 Okayu flat!
But in a minute it's 100,000 Okayu...
えっ、10万おかゆ！？
Eh, 100,000 Okayu!?
払います！今すぐ1万おかゆ払います！
I'll pay! I'll pay 10,000 Okayu right now!
ほら、ご覧の通りまっさらにしておいたよ
See, just as you can see, I made it spotless.
すごすぎます！おかゆさん天才！かっこいい！もぐもぐして！
Too amazing! Okayu-san is a genius! So cool! Munch away!
僕のお手ごろ価格かつ革新的なサービスを
お気に召したようで何よりだよ
I'm glad you liked my affordable
and innovative service.
あ、じ、実はもう1個ありまして……
Ah, w-actually, there's one more thing...
昨日えーちゃんのパソコンで勝手に遊んでたら
間違えて初期化しちゃって、データとか全部消えちゃったんだよね
Yesterday, while playing on A-chan's PC without permission,
I accidentally initialized it, and all the data disappeared.
それは難しい仕事だ、100万おかゆほどかかるね
That's a difficult job. It'll cost about 1 million Okayu.
えっ、そ、それは高すぎるんじゃないかな、なんて
Eh, i-isn't that too expensive, or something...
これは面倒な仕事だよ、お嬢さん。こんな厄介な仕事をたったの100万おかゆで完璧に始末してくれる業者他にい無いよ。まあ別に僕は困らないから好きにしてくれたまえ、お先に失礼
This is a troublesome job, miss. There's no other contractor who would clean it up for just 1 million Okayu. Well, do as you like. Excuse me.
払います！100万おかゆ払いますから
見捨てないでおかゆさま！
I'll pay! I'll pay 1 million Okayu,
so don't abandon me, Lady Okayu!
ここをこうして最後に叩けば、ほらデータも元通り！
Hit it like this at the end, and look, the data is back to normal!
なんかあんまり変わってない気が……
It feels like it hasn't changed much...
これでお嬢さんの失敗は全部なかったことになった、よかったね
With this, all the miss's mistakes are as if they never happened. Good for you.
やったー！これで何の憂いも感じず堂々と歩ける！ありがとうおかゆ！
Yay! Now I can walk proudly without a single worry! Thank you, Okayu!
あ、もしもしえーちゃん？探してた犯人見つかったよ
Ah, hello A-chan? I found the culprit you were looking for.
えっ？
Eh?
はい、おしまい
And that's the end of it.
ようやく垂れてるそのお兄ちゃん
Hey, mister who's hanging his head down
何か辛いことあったんか？
It seems like everything's gone wrong
俺で良けりゃ話してくんない？ 力になるぜ
If you tell me I'm happy to listen, I'll help you out
一体どんなことがあった？
What on earth happened to you?
そりゃ酷え話だ兄弟
Aw man, that's pretty rough, buddy
これをやるから元気出しな
Here take this, it'll make you feel happy
金ならまた今度でいいさ
Just pay me back next time you're here
Shanti Shanti Shanti Shanti Shanti Happy Candy
Happy Happy Happy Candy Many Many Money
眠らない夜のチャイナタウン その全てが縄張り
In the sleepless night of Chinatown, everything is a boundary
老若男女問わずお客人
Customers of every kind
使い終わったら捨てりゃいいいい
You can toss them once you bleed 'em dry
今夜も来たのかい お気に召したかい
Back here again for the night, enjoying the taste that you like?
代金はこれくらい ええええ
The price tag is only this high, eh, eh, eh?
払えないのかい ならばしょうがない
Can't pay? Then there's no choice
君にぴったりの仕事があるからこっちについてきな
There's a job that suits you perfectly, so come with me
焼かれた酒場 剥がれた女
A woman who's been burned, a man who's been deceived
しゃがれた看板 掲げた大男
A hoarse signboard, a large shadow cast
たかだかナイフで刺されたような者じゃあ
It's like being written with an invisible pen
端からアイツの思惑通りだ
It's just as they expected from the start
気狂ってる目 目散歩中
Crazy eyes while out on the street
痴おうるとでお前所得
Selling blood? It makes sense to me
提灯と竜胆 咲かせた果てに
The result of paper lanterns blooming
もう真の真を奏でたまえ
Is faith in false idols
だまれ すわれ だまれ
Shut your mouth, sit down, shut your mouth
なぐれ なぐれ なぐれ
Punch it in, punch it in, punch it in
しばれ しばれ しばれ
Tie them up, tie them up, tie them up
ばらせ ばらせ ばらせ
Cut 'em up, cut 'em up, cut 'em up
今夜分のどうだい お気に召したかい
How about tonight? Did you notice me?
代金はこれくらい 生きてればお客人
This is about the right amount, alive, then it's my clientele
死んでれば商材 手際良く無駄なく転がすビジネス
Dead, then it's mine now as well, demand and supply in transactional hell
どっちを向いてんだ
So are you here to buy or sell?
ようおうな垂れてるそのお嬢ちゃん
Hey missy who's hanging your head down
俺で良けりゃ話してくんない？
If you're okay with me, talk to me
ようおんな垂れてるその兄ちゃん
Hey mister, who's hanging his head down,
何か辛い事あったんか？
did something rough happen to you?
俺で良けりゃ話してくんない？
If it's okay with me, won't you talk?
力になるぜ
I'll help you out.
どっちを向いてんだ
Which way are you facing?
いやもう慣れてるその情ちゃん
Hey missy, who's used to that,
これで良けりゃ話してくんない？
if this is fine, won't you talk to me?
しおん 誕生日おめでとう！
Shion, happy birthday!
ありがとう！嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm so happy!
いや、僕たちのシャンティよすぎないか？
Man, isn't our "Shanti" way too good?
いや、本当によかった！ねえ！
Yeah, it was really great! Right?
シャンティに関してはさ、シャンティを歌い出すさ
Regarding "Shanti", when we were talking about singing "Shanti",
50年前くらいから一緒に歌いたいって言ってたのよ
you said you wanted to sing it together since about 50 years ago, right?
50年前から言ってたのがようやく今日結ばれました
And what you've been saying since 50 years ago finally came true today!
そうだね、おめでとう本当に！
That's right, congratulations, truly!
ありがとう本当に！
Thank you so much!
え、ちなみに50年前何で僕と一緒にシャンティ歌いたかったの？
Oh, by the way, why did you want to sing "Shanti" with me 50 years ago?
えなんか、やっぱかっこいい曲じゃんか。そうだな、かっこよく一緒に歌いたいなと思って、
Um, well, it's such a cool song, you know. I thought it'd be cool to sing it together,
おかゆかっこいいからさ。
because Okayu is so cool.
ええ、ありがとう！しおんちゅーしとげよっか？え？
Eh, thank you! Shall I give you a Shion kiss? Eh?
してくれるの？明日 に？明日ね？明日ね？そうだよね。
Will you? Tomorrow? Tomorrow, right? Tomorrow, right? That's right.
でもさ、シャンティは確かにかっこいい感じだったけどさ、しおん冒頭のなに導入に入ってたアニメでお金取られてなかった？
But you know, "Shanti" definitely had a cool vibe, but Shion, didn't you get your money taken in the anime intro at the beginning?
なんかさ、その、お金に取られたんだよね。取られて、なんか他人事だけど、そのお金に取られたんだよね。
Something like that, yeah, my money got taken. Taken... well, it's someone else's problem, but my money got taken.
なんかさ、僕にお金取られてたみたいだったでしょ？
It looked like my money was getting taken, right?
111万おかえんね？
1.11 million... Okahn?
おかえん取られてたけどさ、でもさおかえんが全部直してくれたじゃん！
You had your Okahn taken, but you know, Okahn fixed all of it!
なかったことにしてくれ、あでも待って、通報されてるそれ。
Pretend it never happened—oh wait, aren't you getting reported for that?
ねえねえ、あれ小指赤な？え、でもあれ人差し指についてるみたいだけど。えでもやっぱほら、そういう、そういうさ、そういうのあるじゃん、けっ
Hey hey, is that your pinky? Eh, but it looks like it's on your index finger. But you know, there's stuff like that, right?
まあ、確かにしおんは人差し指ぐらいがちょうどいいかもね。そうだよね、だって、ないじゃんね。
Well, true, Shion's index finger is probably just right. That's right, because you don't have one, right?
やっぱこの指に絶対つけなきゃいけないなんてたぶんない。やっぱ好きな指でいいじゃんね。
There's probably no rule saying you must put it on this finger. Any finger you like is fine, right?
そうだよね、確かにね。小指なんだ。うん、そういうにしとこうかな。
That's right, true. It's a pinky. Yeah, let's go with that.
いや可愛いなの、すごい可愛い！
Man, it's so cute, super cute!
ね、いいネックレスも付けちゃってさ。
Right, and you've even got a nice necklace on.
本当だよ、かっこいい！ね、遊戯王みたいな感じでいいよね、すごく。ね、かっこいい！
Seriously, it's cool! It's like Yu-Gi-Oh, really good, isn't it? So cool!
すごいいいよ！
It's super good!
こうやってやってる、こうやってやってね、言ってる。かっこいい！これみんなスクショタイムだよ！
Doing this, doing this and saying... Cool! Everyone, this is screenshot time!
かっこいい！かっこいいね！まあ何はともあれしおん、本当にお誕生日おめでとう！
Cool! So cool! Well, anyway, Shion, happy birthday from the bottom of my heart!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
じゃあ僕100万年後も一緒にいてくれる？もちろんだよ、しおん！
So will you stay together with me 100 million years from now? Of course I will, Shion!
そうだよね！うん、明日結婚しようね！
That's right! Yep, let's get married tomorrow!
うん、明日ね！うん、明日ね！
Yep, tomorrow! Yep, tomorrow!
うん、なんか声が聞こえる。
Mm, I hear some voice...
しおちゃおきて！
Shio-chan, wake up!
眠っちゃだめ！いたわ！何してんのねねち？
Don't fall asleep! Ouch! What are you doing, Nenecchi?
よかった。今寝たら、もれなく死ぬよ。
Thank goodness. If you fall asleep now, you'll definitely die.
何ここさむ！吹雪いてるんだけど。
Why is it so cold here?! It's blizzard-ing.
ここは宇宙最高峰の氷高を誇る山、ねねねしと！
This is Neneneshit, the mountain boasting the highest ice peak in the universe!
私たちは人類の希望を背負って、この山の頂上を制覇するためにやってきた。
We came carrying the hopes of humanity to conquer the summit of this mountain.
何これ収録始まってる？しかし、超時間いわたる吹雪にさらされ絶対絶命！
What, is recording starting? However, exposed to hours-long blizzards, we're in a dire situation!
どんどん低下する体温を保つため、二人は抱きしめ合うのだった！
To maintain our plummeting body temperatures, the two had to embrace each other!
は？
Huh?
うわ、骨がー！
Ugh, my bones are—!
しお、この挑戦が終わったら決闘しよう！するかっ！
Shion, when this challenge is over, let's duel! Like I'd do that!
脱力
Collapse.
あれ、何ここ？
Huh, what is this place?
野球場？
A baseball stadium?
カウント2スーパースリー！
Count, two strikes, three balls!
自分で行ってる！ツーアウト満塁！ホームランなら一発逆転、サヨナラ試合即終了！
Doing it yourself! Two outs, bases loaded! A home run turns the tables, walk-off game ends instantly!
俺たちの青春が、この打席にかかってる！
Our youth is riding on this at-bat!
しおん野球知らんから何言ってんのかちょっとわかんない。
Shion doesn't know baseball, so I don't really know what you're saying.
マネージャー！
Manager!
うわ、しおマネージャーなの？ここでホームランを打ったら、私と付き合ってくね！
Whoa, Shion's the manager? If I hit a home run here, you'll go out with me!
うそつきます！
I'm lying!
カキーん！
Clang!
はあ
Haah...
あ
Ah...
あーなんか変な夢見た気がするんだけど
I feel like I had a weird dream...
頭痛っ
My head hurts!
あ、ちょうどいいところに水置いてあんじゃん
Oh, there's water right where I need it.
ぷはー！きくー！
Phew! That hits the spot!
あれ？飲んだね、シオンちゃん
Huh? You drank it, Shion-chan?
飲んでね、いつの間にか、ぐうびっといっちゃったね、シオンちゃん
You drank it before you even knew it, didn't you, Shion-chan?
思いっきり飲んだけど、ねねち、まさかシオンに毒を…
I drank it with all my might, but Nenechi, don't tell me you put poison in Shion's...
くっくっくっ
Hehehe...
くっくっでシオンちゃんに質問です
Hehe, I have a question for Shion-chan.
なんか始まった。すっごい！ホロライブメンバーの中で恋人になりたいのは誰！？
Something started. Wow! Out of all the Hololive members, who do you want to be your lover?!
おかゆ！
Okayu!
違う！
Wrong!
さっきから何やってんの？
What have you been doing this whole time?
次の質問、ほれ薬飲んでも効かないってどういうこと！？
Next question, what do you mean the love potion doesn't work?!
ほれ薬飲んだんかお前
You drank a love potion?
だって、おかゆ先輩にどんなほれ薬使ってるんだか聞かないと、おかゆがほれ薬みたいなもんなんだよ
Because if I don't ask Okayu-senpai what kind of love potion she uses, Okayu herself is basically a love potion!
やだ、ねねちおしゃべりうるさすぎたい
No way, Nenechi, you talk way too much!
えって言うかさ、ねねちそんなにシオンのこと好きだったの？
I mean, Nenechi, do you really like Shion that much?
いや、次の収録まで暇だったから遊んでただけー
Nah, I was just playing around because I had free time until the next recording!
ぴっ
*Beep*
ほらしおんよ
Look, Shion.
だいいしゅーだいしゅき 作詞・作曲：佐々木喫茶
Dai Shuu Dai Shuki (Lyrics & Music: Sasaki Kissa)
まっちょ げっちゅね、それいつもちょ、しょきしょげで、はじけたピーピーマイ、ルーレットごっと
Match you, get you, yeah, you're always so jumpy, bursting pee-pee-my roulette game
スタートきとげと、いそいといと
Start, kick, get, hurry, hurry!
えいきゅーせいきゅー、さっきめっきのきゅー、1ミリのすきまにダイビング
Eternal, sacred, shining quickly cute, diving into a 1mm gap!
ラブかんぺきぜんぶコンプうっせあっぷ、いざいざいざいざ、せーのっさん！
Love is totally all complete, shut up, now, now, now, now, ready, one, two, three!
だってきょうはゴットメンタル、いっそマッシュきちゃれんじゃー
Because today is God Mental, let's just go full-on challenger!
ちょっとだけセンチメンタル
Just a little sentimental.
でしゅきだいしゅき、いちにっさん、はーっ！
Desuki, dai suki, one, two, three, hah!
なみぬめもめもめもめも、みれないの、たちづてとととととがふれて
Waves, eyes, notes, notes, notes, can't look, tachi, tute, to, to, to, to touching...
だいきゅーだいしゅきになれ、もっときゅきゅきゅきゅっときょうせいらぶ！
Become super huge and beloved, even more cute, cute, cute, cute, forced love!
あのね、くりおねつけてるハート、でもね、この胸見せかさないで
You know, the heart clione attached, but you know, don't show off this chest!
だいきゅーだいしゅきになれ、あしたじゃナイなんておわってんね
Become super huge and beloved, saying "not tomorrow" is so over.
まっちょ げっちゅみっけっちゅわちゅちゅ、しょきしょきでからぶるきゅーでぃまい
Match you, get you, found you, wachu, choppy-choppy, empty cute-y-my
るーれっとちょっととっぷ、いさんきゅーしーやーいーやーいーや
Roulette, little top, thank you, see ya, yeah, yeah, yeah!
でもせーのっさんってきょうはまとめって
But, ready, one, two, three, today let's wrap it up!
うるわしきちゃれんじゃー、はーっとかいたおとめしょん
Beautiful challenger, maidenhood written with a heart!
でしゅきだいしゅきいちにっさん、はいっ！
Desuki, dai suki, one, two, three, let's go!
なみぬめもめもめもめもみれないの、たちづてとととととがふれて
Waves, eyes, notes, notes, notes, notes, can't look, tachi, tute, to, to, to, to touching...
だいきゅーだいしゅきになれ、もっときゅきゅきゅきゅっときょうせいらぶ！
Become super huge and beloved, even more cute, cute, cute, cute, forced love!
あのね、まりおねあやつられていで、でもねそれもねわるくはないで
You know, marionette being manipulated, but you know, that's not so bad either!
だいきゅーだいしゅきになれ、あしたじゃナイなんておわってんね
Become super huge and beloved, saying "not tomorrow" is so over.
ふれんどりーなふりして、しゅうはすうをみださないで
Acting friendly, don't disrupt the frequency!
いわつきのみわくのりぷりあみなるみなる
Rock-bound, seductive rippli, aminal, minal!
なみぬめもめもめもめもみれないの、たちづてとととととがふれて
Waves, eyes, notes, notes, notes, notes, can't look, tachi, tute, to, to, to, to touching...
だいきゅーだいしゅきになれ、もっときゅきゅきゅきゅっときょうせいらぶ！
Become super huge and beloved, even more cute, cute, cute, cute, forced love!
あのねくりおねつけてるハート、でもねこの胸みすかさないで
You know, the heart clione attached, but you know, don't see through this chest!
だいきゅーだいしゅきになれ、あしたじゃないなんておわってんね
Become super huge and beloved, saying "not tomorrow" is so over.
なみぬめもめもめもめもみれないの、たちづてとととととがふれて
Waves, eyes, notes, notes, notes, notes, can't look, tachi, tute, to, to, to, to touching...
だいきゅーだいしゅきになれ、もっときゅきゅきゅきゅっときょうせいらぶ！
Become super huge and beloved, even more cute, cute, cute, cute, forced love!
あのねくりおねつけてるハート、でもねこの胸みすかさないで
You know, the heart clione attached, but you know, don't see through this chest!
だいきゅーだいしゅきになれ、あしたじゃないなんておわってんね
Become super huge and beloved, saying "not tomorrow" is so over.
しおんちゃん誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday, Shion-chan!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
なんかちょっと遅めだねえ。
Man, that's a bit late, huh?
そうだよ、ちょっと遅くなっちゃっ…
True, it got a bit late.
ちょっと遅くなっちゃったか。
It got a bit late, yeah.
ちょっとお待たせ！
Sorry to keep you waiting.
あ、
Ah...
久しぶりのマブダチです！
It's our first 3D live in a while!
すごい揃った！
That's so true!
マブダチだし当たり前か。
Well, us being besties is a given, right?
当たり前だよ！
Of course!
え、でもさ、二人で3D初めてだしさ、よ。
Though, this is our first time doing 3D together, you know?
そんなことある？
Is that even a thing?
マブな、マブなのに、うん。
Besties... We're besties, but...
ふしぎだなあ。
Huh? Strange.
え、え、初めてってつか、そんなわけ…ないよね？
No way, is it really our first time?
ないな、ないな。なんか初めてな気がするだけ？そうゆうことか。記憶喪失だから。
No, no, no! It just feels like it's our first time?
ちょっと忘れちゃっ…忘れんなよ！
Wait, don't forget! Don't forget, okay?
もうやだ！忘れんなよ、マブのこと。
No way! Don't forget about Mab!
ちょっとそういえば後ろの絵、
Come to think of it, the illustration in the back...
可愛すぎんか！
So cute!
ハートしてる？
Heart-shaped?
ハートしてるわ。しゅんちゃ、腹ぺこっちじゃな？
Heart-shaped? Shion-chan, your stomach's growling!
笑っ…ねねおじ？
Laughing...
ねねおじですか？
Are you a nene-ojisan?
あ、後ろも素敵だよ、こっちの、本体の後ろも。
Well, the back is cute, and the back of our main bodies too.
ちょっと、や、やめてよー！
Come on, stop it!
ちょっと、はずかしい！
Come on, how embarrassing!
で、で、も、しゅんちゃ、ね、ねねちゃ、しゅんちゃと付き合いたいから！
Wait, Nene-chi, I want to hang out with Shion-chan!
え、やっぱねねっちって、しゅんこと、もしやしてす、す、好きなの？！
Wait, Nene-chi?! Could it be that you...
そうでもないよーん！
That's not it!
でゅくす。
Yikes.
あー、今日も疲れ…
Man, I'm so tired today.
すいちゃん、何してんの？
Suichan, what are you doing?
だって、ぼくは、星だから…
Because I'm empty inside...
あ、しおんちゃん、こんにちは。
Oh, Shion-chan, hello.
こ、こんにちは。どうしたの？
Hello? What's wrong?
最近満たされない気持ちが大きくなって、ついに感情を失ってしまったの。
Lately, this empty feeling has grown so big, I've finally lost all my emotions.
え、かわいそう。
Oh dear, poor thing.
もう何もする気が起きなくて、こうして床に突っ伏していることが自分の使命だと思えてきた。
I don't feel like doing anything anymore, so I thought face-planting on the floor was my destiny.
ずっとその状態で話すのやめて！
Stop talking like that!
アニメーション組む人も私がずっとこのままでいたほうが楽だろうし。
Even the animation team would prefer me to stay like this.
すいちゃん、ほら！
Suichan, come on!
美味しいもの食べれば気分も上がってくるって！
If you eat something delicious, your mood will pick up!
ほら、買ってきたから一緒に食べよう。
Look, I bought this so let's eat together.
すみません、いただきます。
Thank you very much. I'll dig in.
丁寧ご。
So polite.
だめだ。美味しいはずなのに、全然感情が動かない。
It's no good. It should be delicious, but my emotions just won't budge.
しおんの分は？
As for Shion's share...
やはり食事では私の心を動かすことができない。
Meals just can't stir my heart.
嫌な食べ物も美味しい。いや、それだけ綺麗に残しやがって！
I hate that the food is delicious, yet you just leave it looking pretty!
次はファンレターを読もう。
Next, let's read some fan letters.
ほら、こんなに大きなダンボールにいっぱい来てる。
Look, we've got a ton of them in this big cardboard box!
ありがたい限りです。
I'm deeply grateful.
しせいよう、ほら見てすいちゃん、歌がとっても好きですってメッセージ来てるよ。
Shiseiyou, look at this, Suichan! There's a message saying, "I just love your singing!"
歌？
Singing?
そうだよ、すいちゃんには歌があるじゃん！自分を信じて！
That's right, Suichan, you have your singing! Just believe in yourself!
そっか。私には歌があるんだ。
I see... I have my singing.
どうぞ。
Here you go.
野菜が食べれないところ以外は全部大好きです。意外。
"Except for vegetables, I love everything." Oh, wait.
意外。
Wait, wait.
ネガティブにとらえてそう。
She took it negatively...
すいちゃんは！
Suichan!
今日もかわいい！
Today you're cute too!
怖い怖い怖い怖い！すいちゃん爆発しないで！
You're scary, scary, scary! Suichan, don't explode!
すいちゃんは変色だけどかわいい。
Suichan is discolored, but cute.
あー、引きずってる。
Ugh, I'm dragging this out.
仕方ない。
Fine.
シオン地下の超高級素材を使用して作ったこの魔法薬を与えよう。
I made this magic potion using Shion's subterranean ultra-luxury materials. Drink this!
なんでそんな魔女みたいなことを。
Why are you saying it like a witch?
魔女だよ！
I am a witch!
これはひとびの飲めば何でも食べれるようになる魔法の薬。
This is a magic medicine that lets you eat anything if you drink just one bottle.
人が飲んでいい色してない。
It doesn't look like something humans should drink.
ちょっとまずいけど、作るのにシオンのGDPレベルのお金がかかってるから、大事に飲んで！
It's a bit nasty, but making it cost Shion's GDP level in money, so drink it carefully!
いや、ちょっ！
Hey, woah!
はいっき、いっき、いっき！
Drink up, drink up, drink up!
見せられないよ。
You're cute!
シオンのGDPが！
Shion's GDP!
何入ってんだこれ！
What is even in this?!
こんなもん飲めるか！
Can you even drink stuff like this?!
くわ！
Rawr!
食べ なく ちゃ 食べ なく ちゃ
I have to eat, I have to eat!
嫌 な こと 忘れ させ て ？
Let me forget those unpleasant things, okay?
食べなくちゃ 食べなくちゃ
I gotta eat, I gotta eat.
嫌なことは忘れさせて？
Make me forget all the things I hate?
いかないでね、ねえ いかないで？
Don't go, hey, please don't go?
君の体温と、心臓。
Your body temperature and your heartbeat.
アイ アイ アイラヴユー と
Ai, ai, I love you, and
アイ アイ アイ ヘイ ユー
Ai, ai, hey you.
君のすべてが あたしならいいのに
I wish all of you belonged to me instead.
満たされない、満たされない
Unsatisfied, unsatisfied,
満たされない、のは、フィーリング、
What's unsatisfied is the feeling.
愛されたい、愛されたい
I want to be loved, I want to be loved,
愛されたいのは 秘密事項！
What I want to be loved is a secret!
吐かなくちゃ もう 吐かなくちゃ
I gotta throw up, I gotta throw up,
ざめざめ泣いても 終電だ
Even if I cry bitterly, it's the last train.
可愛くない、可愛くない
Not cute, not cute,
可愛くないから 消えたい？
Do you want to disappear because you're not cute?
現在開発中の
Currently under development,
アンケート調査 ツール
a questionnaire survey tool:
「あたしの日々が あの子ならいいのに」
"I wish my days were like that girl's."
満たされない、満たされない
Unsatisfied, unsatisfied,
満たされない、から、嫌い。
Unsatisfied, so I hate it.
愛されたい、愛されたい
I want to be loved, I want to be loved,
愛されたいのは 地球規模！
What I want to be loved is on a global scale!
満たされない、満たされない
Unsatisfied, unsatisfied,
満たされないから 嫌い。
Unsatisfied, so I hate it.
愛されたい、愛されたい
I want to be loved, I want to be loved,
愛されたいのは 地球規模！
What I want to be loved is on a global scale!
わあー！すごーい！
Wow! That's amazing!
ひとりじゃないよ！
You're not alone!
しおんちゃん、ありがとー！すいちゃん！
Shion-chan, thank you! Suichan!
しゃっくりが…ありがとー！すいちゃん！
I got the hiccups... Thank you! Suichan!
しゃっくりなんて初めて言われた
That's the first time I've ever been told hiccups.
今日初めて言われた！初めて言われた！
I was told that for the first time today!
え、なんでなんで？しゃっくり呼んでくれたの？
Eh, why why? Did you call me because of hiccups?
え、すいちゃん、え、今日は、あの、ゲストで、お粥と、お粥以外、みんな、あの、3Dで2人並ぶの初めてだったの。
Eh, Suichan, today, except for Okayu, it was everyone's first time appearing in 3D as a pair.
え！初めてじゃん、確かに！
Eh! That is your first time, true!
え、そうなんだよ！うちらすいちゃん初めてじゃん！
Eh, that's right! It's our first time with Suichan!
え、そうなんだよ！こんにちは！こんにちは、はじめまして！
Eh, that's right! Hello! Hello, nice to meet you!
え、バカにしてるの？
Eh, are you making fun of me?
いやめっちゃ嬉しかったんだよ呼んでもらえて！え、本当？
No, I was really happy you invited me! Eh, really?
ってかだってさ、なかなか会うこともね、そうないしさ。
I mean, we don't get to see each other very often.
今まで、そうライブでちょっと挨拶したりとかそう、そう、クリスマスパーティね！
Up until now, we've just greeted each other at lives... yeah, the Christmas party!
呼びました！めっっちゃ嬉しかったよ呼んでくれて！
I invited you! I was sooo happy you invited me!
なんかさ、あのさ、どこかからさ、しおんちゃんが私のこと気になってるって…
It's like, someone somewhere told me that Shion-chan was interested in me...
でた！どこどこどこ！？どこで聞いたの？気になってんの？と思って！
There it is! Where, where, where!? Where did you hear that? Are you interested? I thought!
めっちゃ喋るそれ真剣のことどうなんですか？
You talk so much, what is that really about?
え、気になってる。
Eh, I'm interested.
え、どこで会ってんの！？そう！ここですごいさ、別々に気になってはいないって言われたらおもろいけど。
Eh, where did you meet!? That's right! It would be funny if you said you weren't particularly interested here.
別に、え、別に会ってないんだけど
Not really, eh, we haven't really met.
え、なんでこの曲選んだの？え、すいちゃんとあ、すいちゃんってめっちゃ歌が上手くて、本当隣に並ぶのもちょっと恐れ多いぐらい歌が上手くて、
Eh, why did you choose this song? Eh, Suichan is so good at singing, her singing is so good that I'm almost scared to stand next to her,
そんな！そんな！
No way! No way!
え、そうだから、かっこよすぎたら後ろについていけないと思って、綺麗な曲、綺麗な曲ならギリギリいけると思って、でもしおんちゃんが上手すぎたね！
Eh, if it was too cool, I couldn't keep up, so I thought a pretty song would be just barely manageable, but Shion-chan was too good!
え、そんなことないです！しおんちゃんが上手すぎたよね！
Eh, that's not true! Shion-chan was too good!
もうこのね、食虫植物みたいな、曲長はもうしおんちゃんの、え、本当？特段ですよ！
Like this 'Carnivorous Plant' song, the song director is already Shion's... eh, really? It's exceptional!
似合ってた？めっちゃ似合ってた！うん、やった！嬉しいな！
Did it suit me? It suited you so much! Yeah, I did it! I'm so happy!
みんな「ママ、ママ」みたい。ママ…
Everyone is like 'Mama, Mama'. Mama...
お母さんに褒められたみたいな、どんどんさ後ろに下がっちゃって…
It's like being praised by your mother, you keep stepping back...
どうぞどうぞ、そう、なんか、なんか恥ずかしいって気持ちになっちゃうかもしれない。
Go ahead, please, yeah, it might make you feel kind of embarrassed.
え、あとね、めっちゃ嬉しかった！あの、楽曲のイラストもね！
Eh, also, I was super happy! The song's illustration too!
こっちだ！そう！しおんちゃんが
Over here! That's right! Shion-chan...
用意してくれたんですけど
You prepared it for us...
どうですか 感想？
How do you like it?
コンセプト？
The concept...
Concept?
食中食？
Food, food...
こうやって言ってる。
That's what you're saying.
ねぇ なんかさ なんか見える。
Doesn't it look like?
こんななんか食べてる。
It looks like...
なんか食べられそうだな シオンに。
It looks like we're gonna get eaten, Shion.
そうそう。
Yeah.
ねぇ えいって。
Look at that.
なんかさ、ヤンデレ感あるよね。
There's kind of a Yandere vibe, you know?
え、あるね。完全にね、狙ってるよたぶん。
Yeah, there is. Definitely targeting you.
めちゃめちゃ狙われてるよ命。
You're definitely being targeted for your life.
これ完全にさ、催眠がかかって――
This is totally like, hypnotized...
なんか食べられた後なんだもん。
It's like what happens after you get eaten, huh?
「えっ」てことあるね。
"Et"? Does that mean...
はい、終わり！
All right, it's over!
はい、ということで、シオンちゃんお誕生日おめでとうございました！
All right, so Shion-chan, happy birthday!
また一緒に歌おうね！
Let's sing together again sometime!
ありがとう、すいちゃん！バイバーイ！
Thank you, Suisei! Bye-bye!
この混沌とした令和のインターネットを照らす一筋の光
Shining as a single ray of light
電子の海を漂うオタクに笑顔を
Bringing a smile to the otaku drifting in the electronic sea
未来の平和をお約束 騒々しいだけどまかせとけ
Promising peace for the future, it's hectic, but leave it to me
インターネット・エンジェル ただいま降臨！
Internet Angel, descending right now!
社会をやめろ 家族をやめろ 人間関係をやめろ
Quit society, quit family, quit human relations
今すぐ薄暗い部屋で青白いライトを浴びろ
Right now, bathe in the pale light in a dimly lit room
大丈夫 怖かったこと全部上書きするからね
It's okay, I'll overwrite everything you were afraid of
現実よりも crazy for you
More than reality, crazy for you
おかしくなりそうなほど情報過多のインターネット
An internet so information-heavy it makes you feel like you're going crazy
今すぐ救ってあげるよ ダーリン ダーリン
I'll save you right now, darling, darling!
ウソはウソだと見抜けるしこの愛は暴走しちゃうし
I can tell lies are lies, and this love is going to run wild
壊れてしまうけど
And it's gonna break down, but...
考えなくていいんだよ
You don't have to think about it!
もうすぐ楽になるからね
You'll be happy soon enough!
脳内に乱反射する poison radio
Poison radio reflecting back into your brain
麻薬より甘いよ
Sweeter than drugs
いいね 良くないね キミにとっては毒だね
It's no good, it's no good, it must be toxic for you
いいね 良くないね それでも飲むんだね
It's no good, it's no good, but you still drink it up
いいね 良くないね 二人のヒミツだね
It's no good, it's no good, it's our little secret
わたしだけ見ててね
Just look at me, okay?
まるですてきのようにほほえむ 強めの幻覚 internet girl
Smiling like an angel, strong illusions internet girl
そして悪魔みたいにささやく アナタだけのデパス needy girl
Whispering like a demon, just for you, needy girl
浅い眠りと承認欲求のオーバードーズ
An overdose of light sleep and a need for validation
脳天直撃するわたしたちだけの宗教と光
Our own religion and light, striking straight to the brain
倫理より激しく生きた宇宙すら侵食する恋
Love that invades even the cosmos, living more fiercely than ethics
何度も送られる毒電波を優しさだけで包んで
Toxic radio waves sent over and over, wrapped only in kindness
逆さまのコンピュータと断片的なカウンセリング
Upside-down computers and fragmentary counseling
きらめく屋上で奏でた 夢見心地の旋律
Playing a dreamlike melody on a sparkling rooftop
夕暮れ時にさよならの練習をして
Practicing saying goodbye at twilight
壊して愛して許して狂って 狂って狂って甘く狂わせて
Break it, love it, forgive it, go crazy, go crazy, go crazy, let it make you sweetly crazy
ゆらぎ始める世界 曖昧になる風景
The world begins to sway, scenery becoming ambiguous
アナタだけが映っているメモリー
A memory where only you are reflected
神様なんてないよ
There's no such thing as God!
このふざけたインターネットは七色のサイケデリック
This goofy internet is a rainbow psychedelic
SNSという瓶詰め地獄に救済を
Save us in this bottled hell called SNS
過去の歴史は見ないふりアナタのためならすぐそばに
Pretending not to see past history, for your sake, right by your side
インターネット・エンジェル かわいく参上！
Internet Angel, coming in cute!
まるですてきのように抱きつく 強めの幻覚 internet girl
Hugging you like an angel, strong illusions internet girl
そして悪魔みたいにキスする アナタだけの2D girl
And then like a demon, kissing you, 2D girl
angel angel angel angel
はーい！というわけで、インターネットオーバードーズでしたー！
And with that, Internet Overdose!
めちゃめちゃね、これも
That was so much fun!
かわいい演出になってた感じかなって思います。
I think it turned out to have really cute staging.
見てましたか、ちゃんと？
Did you all watch it properly?
はー、ちょっと使いすぎちゃった。
Haah, I used up too much energy...
はい、というわけでね、どうでしたかここまでのライブは？みんな楽しんでくれましたか？
So, how was the live so far? Did everyone enjoy it?
そうってね、言い忘れちゃったんですけど、ゲストのね、ゲストライブの前に、なんか、なんかあったでしょ？謎の、なんか、何あれ？急に何あれって、そう、なったでしょみんな多分。
That's right, I forgot to mention, before the guest live stream, there was something... mysterious, right? Like, "What was that all of a sudden?" Everyone must have thought that.
そう、実はですね、あのゲストライブの前に、MMDのね、動画を、アニメ動画をちょっと作って差し込んでもらいました。
Well, actually, before the guest live, we made an MMD anime video and had it inserted.
踏みましたか？曲に、曲の内容に寄せてる感じになってたんですけど。
Did you catch it? It was styled to match the content of the song.
面白かったですか？面白かったですよね？面白かったんだよね？
Was it interesting? It was interesting, right? It was interesting, wasn't it?
はい、というわけでね、そんな感じで
Right, so with that being said,
え？あ！あれは！なん、なんだあれ！てわけで、あの、この後ですね配信終了後にプレミア公開します！
Eh? Ah! That's...! What, what is that?! So, right after this stream ends, we'll have a premiere release!
「東京シャンデリランデブー」のね、歌ってみたを作りました！というわけで、この後配信すぐ配信終わってすぐに、
We made a cover of "Tokyo Chandelier Rendezvous"! So right after this stream ends,
あの、プレミア公開するので、これも見てねー！じゅじゅじゅじゅーん！
um, we'll be premiering it, so please check that out too! Tada!
はい、というわけでこの後の曲は「シャンデリア」です！聞いてね！
Right, so the next song is "Chandelier"! Take a listen!
叶わないないないの妬みそうを
Envy of wishes that won't ever come true,
行き場ない情熱と苦しさを
Passion with nowhere to go and the torment
君から貰ったシャララララランダラ
I received from you, shalala-larandala.
衝動からは抗えないわ
I can't resist this impulse.
あとちょっとそっとずっとえっと秘密ごとは
A bit more, gently, always, um, secrets
譲れないわ叶わないわ
I won't yield, they won't come true,
あとちょっとの距離イメージ秘密ごとは
A little more distance, imagining secrets,
飾らないわ忘れないわまだまだ
I won't adorn them, I won't forget, even now.
ラッキー ジャンキー ハッピー だらだら 空気ったらウェイ
Lucky, junky, happy, lounging, cutting through the air, yeah!
なら一難去ってまた一難ね お願いぎゅっとハグして
If one trouble passes after another, please hug me tight!
ダキダキ ハッピー はたまた空気ってマイウェイ
Daki-daki happy, or else cutting the air my way,
ならお願い聞いて頭がいいんでしょ？
So please listen, you're smart, right?
叶わないないないの妬みそうを
Envy of wishes that won't ever come true,
行き場ない情熱と痛みをも
Passion with nowhere to go and the pain too,
君から奪ったシャララララランダラ
I stole from you, shalala-larandala.
衝動からは逃げられないわ
I can't escape this impulse.
ハッピー ハッピー ハッピー まだまだ馬鹿みたいってウェイ
Happy, happy, happy, still acting like a fool, yeah!
なら一難去ってまた一難ね お願いぎゅっとラブリーな
If one trouble passes after another, please give me a lovely one!
ダキダキ ハッピー まだまだあいあいあいあいあい愛に
Daki-daki happy, still ai-ai-ai-ai-ai-ain,
お願い聞いてハネハタシでしょ？
Please listen, it's out of the question, right?
叶わないないないの妬みそうを
Envy of wishes that won't ever come true,
行き場ない情熱と痛みとを
Passion with nowhere to go and pain too,
君から貰ったシャララララランダラ
I received from you, shalala-larandala.
衝動からは抗えないわ
I can't resist this impulse.
心の底まで近づいてまだ会いたいする狂おしいデザイア
Getting close to the bottom of my heart, a mad desire to see you still,
心の底まで2人で近づいてほら
Getting close to the bottom of my heart together, look—
衝動からは抗えないわ
I can't resist this impulse.